# **IVAN YAPPUTRA YAPPI**

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

+6287834950559 | ivanyapputrax1@gmail.com | Linkedin/IvanYapputra | Github/Vayxius

## **ABOUT:**

An experienced full stack developer with a tendency to back-end, prefer to stay up to date with the whole development process from database structure to mobile responsive views and analytics. Moreover, I dive deep into company business processes and I won't hesitate to suggest any ideas aimed to improve it from the development side.

## **EDUCATION:**

## Universitas Widyatama | 2017 - 2021

Bachelor Degree in Informatics Engineering, 3.75/4.00

 Thesis: Implementation of an Artificial Intelligence System for Detecting Respiratory Diseases Using Web-Based Telemedicine Methods

## **WORK EXPERIENCES:**

## PT. Inexia Techno Property

Full Stack Developer | Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

- Ensure user satisfaction and retention by providing responsive tech support.
- Build and maintain application using Laravel framework that allows the admin or agent to manage data.
- Created database with properties table, roles table, post table, images table, and users table for storing information about products and users.

## PT. SMOOETS TEKNOLOGI OUTSOURCING

Frontend Developer | Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

- Built and maintained websites for clients.
- Created and tested applications for websites and company profile using wordpress.
- Filed reports, gathered information and performed research.

## **SKILLS:**

## **Programming Languages**

Python, HTML 5, CSS (version 3), Sass, PHP (version 7), SQL, Javascript, Java, C Sharp, C++.

#### **Framework**

Wordpress, Codeigniter, Laravel, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, Django, Streamlit.

### Libraries

Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Streamlit.

#### Tools

Jupyter Notebook, Sublime, Visual Studio Code, Git, Github.

## **PROJECTS:**

### **Musical Intrument Store**

Web Application

- Built an e-commerce website using Codeigniter to showcase the musical instrument products.
- Created a membership site to create, manage, and sell products.
- Made a customizable checkout process to ensure that customers purchase products easily.

## **Moksa Coffee**

Web Application

- Create a purchase order application using React (frontend) to display a list of food & drinks.
- Create responsive interface design using sass.
- Build API (backend) with nodeJS, using express as framework and using mongoDB (NoSQL) as database.

## The Look E-commerce

Data Analyst

- Analyzing product sales performance at "The Look" store which has decreased in 2020.
- Libraries used: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scipy.
- Deployment: Heroku
- Repository: Github

## **ORGANISATIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

# Japan Community Widyatama | 2017 - 2020

Logistics

- Secured a total of 6 sponsors for the events.
- Ensure successful workflows, schedules, communications on a daily basis.
- Successfully manage Sashimi XI Dungeon

## **ACHIEVEMENTS:**

- 2nd Place in Bandung City Level Blog Design | 2014
- 2nd Place Web Design Competition at Widyatama International Academic Competition and Exhibition Event | 2019